ftdfloristsonline.com 2018-12-25

# Same Day Flower Delivery in by your FTD florist

Your Security and Privacy Are Important to Us  
FTD Florists Online Network ("FTD Florists Online. .FOL.," "we" or "us") is committed to protecting our customers' privacy. We feel it is important that you fully understand the terms and conditions under which we use the information we gather from you through the use of each of our FTD Florists Online Web sites and any other sites that we control (collectively, our "Sites"). Please read this Privacy Policy ("Policy") carefully to understand how we will use and protect your personal information. We will never share your personal information with anyone except as described in this Policy. 

Collection and Use of Information   
In general, you can visit our Sites without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. In order to better provide you with numerous products and services, each of our Sites collects two types of information about its visitors: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. 

1\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
When you visit any of our Sites, we may collect some basic Non-Personally Identifiable Information about you. This information may include information regarding your operating system, browser software, and IP (Internet Protocol) address. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is collected in order to provide you with satisfactory service. We may use the information to detect problems with our server and to administer our Sites. In addition, Non-Personally Identifiable Information is compiled by us and analyzed on an aggregate basis. 

2\. Personally Identifiable Information  
When you place an order or enter a sweepstakes or promotion, we request that you send us Personally Identifiable Information. This information lets us know the specifics of who you are and can be used to identify, contact or locate you. Personally Identifiable Information may consist of: your name, address, telephone number, email address, birth date, billing information (credit card number, expiration date and billing address), occasion type (Valentine's Day, etc.), products purchased, any relevant promotion code and information (for example, reward program account information) and the gift and message recipient's name, address, telephone number, email address and any other information you may provide us ("Personally Identifiable Information" ). We use Personally Identifiable Information for internal purposes, such as confirming and tracking your order, subscription or registration, analyzing trends and statistics, informing you of our new products, services and offers. Personally Identifiable Information is compiled by us and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. 

To serve you better, we may combine Personally Identifiable Information you give us online or through our catalogs. We may also combine that information with publicly available information about you that we may receive from third parties. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and for other promotional purposes. 

We may contract with third-party companies or persons to provide certain services including credit card processing, distribution, data management, promotional services, etc. ("Service Providers"). We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services. We also ask our Service Providers to confirm that their privacy practices are consistent with ours. 

3\. Placing an Order  
When you place an order, we require you to provide us with Personal Information. We use this information to give you a customized experience and to process the orders that you place with us. 

For your shopping convenience, when you place an order, we automatically establish your own Personal Account where information used in placing such order (including billing address, email address, telephone number(s) and rewards program information) is saved. Your Personal Account is password protected from third parties. You may access your Personal Account by requesting your password from us (go to My Account) and then signing in with that password. Afterward, you may change your password, edit your Personal Information or request a password reminder at any time. Our database stores your billing and delivery information, and will automatically transfer it to the order form each time you place an order so that you do not have to re-enter this information when you sign in at subsequent visits. 

The recipient phone number, which you furnish to us when you place an order, is used for delivery purposes. On some occasions, the recipient may be called to schedule delivery. To maintain our high quality standards, we will occasionally contact recipients to ensure satisfaction with their gift. 

back to top

4\. Use of Cookies/Clear GIFs  
Cookies: Like many other commercial sites, our Sites may utilize standard technologies called "cookies" and clear GIFs to collect information about how each of our Sites is used. A cookie is a small data text file, which a Web site stores on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to us. Cookies were designed to help a Web site recognize a user's browser as a previous visitor and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while the user was browsing the site. A cookie cannot be read by a Web site other than the one that set the cookie. Cookies can securely store a customer's password, personalize home pages, identify which parts of a site have been visited or keep track of selections, such as those selected in a "shopping cart." For instance, cookies allow us to pre-populate (or fill in) an email field with your email address if you revisit one of our Sites and place an order. When you place an order, we send a cookie to your hard drive to record the product name, category of product that you ordered, the amount paid, the order number and any referral codes. No Personally Identifiable Information is recorded. When you click through to any one of our Sites from a promotional email, our Service Provider may send a cookie to your hard drive recording your IP address and other related information. 

Clear GIFs: Some of our Service Providers may employ clear GIFs (also known as pixel tags, single pixel GIFs, web beacons or action tags) for our benefit to help us measure advertising effectiveness. Clear GIFs help us better manage content on our Sites by informing us of what content is effective. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of our users. The main difference between the two is that clear GIFs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear GIFs are not tied to your Personally Identifiable Information. Our Service Providers may use clear GIFs: (i) in HTML based emails to determine which emails have been opened by recipients; (ii) to record when products have been ordered from our Sites; and (iii) to track the visitor traffic on our Sites. These clear GIFs allow us to measure the usage of each of our Sites by our visitors and the effectiveness of certain communications and marketing campaigns. We may also use clear GIFs in a similar manner in our own emails and on our Sites. Clear GIFs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear GIF, the Web site would match the clear GIFs identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information can be shared with the advertising company. We may provide such information to our Service Providers but that information can only be used by our Service Providers for our benefit. 

back to top

5\. Interactive Tools  
Within your Personal Account, you have the option to opt in for our additional services, which include a personal date reminder service and a free online address book. We use your contact information so that you may take full advantage of these interactive tools. You may view, edit or opt out of these additional services at anytime. 

back to top

6\. Mergers and Acquisitions  
In the event of a merger, consolidation, or sale or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of Florists Transworld Delivery Inc the owner of FTD Florists Online or its direct or indirect parent company (ies), one of the assets which would generally be transferred to the purchasing or new entity is the information we collect from our customers and store in our customer database. However, the use of this information by any purchasing or surviving entity would be governed by the terms of this Policy, as amended from time to time, including any amendment after such transaction. You, of course, will continue to have the right to opt-out of sharing your information with third parties. 

back to top

7\. Cooperation with Law Enforcement  
We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information, after subpoena or written request, to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful. 

back to top

Security   
We use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. SSL encrypts your order information as additional protection against the decoding of that information by anyone other than us. However, despite all reasonable security precautions and processes, such as password protection, encryption technology, and use of firewall technology, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from our Sites, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we will take commercially reasonable precautions to protect its security on our systems. 

If you open a Personal Account with one of our FTD florist Online websites, your password will be your personal, secret entry code to that Site. When you access your account information, it is kept on a secure server and a password is needed to access any account areas. You can change your password as many times as you like. We recommend that you keep your password in a safe place and that you always sign off your account and close your browser window once you have finished your visit. These precautions will help prevent someone else from accessing your account, especially if you share a computer with other people or use a computer in a public place such as an Internet café or library. 

back to top

Links to Other Web Sites   
Our Sites may contain links to other Web sites. Privacy policies on such linked sites may be different from our Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices and content of these third-party Web sites. You access such linked sites at your own risk. We urge you to follow safe Internet practices and do not supply Personal Information to these Web sites unless you have verified their security and privacy policies. 

back to top

Child Protection   
We take special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. Our Sites are general audience sites. Consumers making purchases on our Sites must have a valid credit card and be 18 years of age or older. It is the policy of FTD Florists Online not to collect personal information on any person under the age of 18 and we request that any person under age 18 not submit any personal information via our sites. Our reminder and greeting services are designed not to gather birth dates (with years) or other personal information for children under 13. 

back to top

Sale, Trade or Rental of Personally Identifiable Information   
We only share Personally Identifiable Information with businesses that we believe to be reputable and that can provide you with offers and information that we think will be of interest to you. If you would like to opt-out of our providing your name and mailing address to third parties, please follow the procedure outlined in the Opt Out / Modify section below. We do share Personally Identifiable Information with our floral and gift distributors for the purpose of fulfilling and delivering your orders. We may offer free promotional emails and send promotional direct mail for products and/or services offered on any one or more of our Sites or from businesses that we believe are reputable, as a service to our prior customers from any of our Sites. You have several options for altering or removing your information from our database at any time: see "Opt Out / Modify" section below. 

back to top

Credit Card   
When making purchases with our network of FTD florist web sites the credit card you provide will be submitted for authorization and if approved charged by each individual florist either at the time the order is taken on the website or upon receipt of the encrypted order information. Processing of the foregoing credit cards follows credit card industry standards. 

As always, consumers making purchases must have a valid credit card, be at least 18 years of age or older, and have a good credit standing. 

back to top

Opt out /Modify   
If you would like to modify or delete your account simply return to any of the floral sites in our network, click on the link called "Your Account". Once you have signed in to your account a menu of options is provided for you to delete or edit your stored account information. 

back to top

Your Consent   
By shopping at our Sites or opening an account with Florists Online florists , you consent to the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by us in the manner specified in this Policy. We, however, have the option to change, modify, or add to the terms and conditions of the Policy at any time. We will inform you of any changes by posting the revised Policy on our Sites. Any customer who does not agree to the revised Policy has the option to opt-out. The Policy will go into effect on the date posted. The new Policy will apply to all current and past users of our Sites and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent. 

For our Sites that accept international orders, if you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide will be transferred to the United States. By using our sites or providing us with your information, you hereby consent to this transfer. In addition, if you provide data about other individuals (such as gift recipients), you agree that you have obtained consent from each such individual to the submission and processing of such information to the terms of this Policy, including without limitation the transfer of such data to the United States. Although we will collect and use your information only as stated in this Policy, laws generally applicable to the protection of personal data in the United States may not be as stringent as those in some users' home jurisdictions. 

back to top
